will you include some cyber security in
the beginner boost that's the question I
just got and the answer is yes because
what is cyber security oh here we go
then my community is going to have fun
with me they the sound's off I should
probably turn their sound up no I can't
hear the sound okay the answer is yes
what is cyber security what does it mean
to be a
hacker honestly cyber security is just a
matter of understanding a system really
well and we won't get into the debate
about whether hacker is the right term
versus cracker and blah blah blah blah
blah go some place be want to study all
that stuff um the fastest grow 32
fastest growing career according to the
Bureau of Labor and statistics and
there's another video about this is
cyber security analyst and at 32% this
year uh with a with a median salary of
something like
$7,000 I think it is so it is still a
very very valid career path it is
definitely one of the career path that
I've considered um you know when when
picking out things for people to do uh
and stuff for you to learn but in fact
it's probably one of the ones that
benefits the most from things like the
command line and and and scripting in
Python and JavaScript and the go
programming and the C the C coding that
we're going to do in the beginner boost
all this stuff is particularly suited
for hackers so but is it directly
related to teaching you cyber security
in the beginner boost yes I mean it's
we're we that's just one of the careers
it's one of the careers that benefits
the most but we don't the beginner boost
is not focused on becoming a hacker so
even if you wear a hoodie on a Sunday on
Cinco de
Mayo you know you can call yourself a
hacker the truth is is that anybody who
understands the low-level part of a
system about how how it works can call
themselves a hacker I have one story
related to this and you can end the
video now but if you don't want to hear
the story I started streaming to Twitch
because I thought I wanted to change my
career path
and finally you know go into cyber
security uh particularly you know red
teaming and breaking in and stuff like
that and so I for the first year in 2020
I started streaming ocp preparation
which is offensive Securities prep
there's lots of amazing streamers by the
way on Twitch to to deal with cyber
security who are employed in cyber
security field and I mean I I have done
cyber security I have definitely hacked
um you're going to have to come to my
stream and get me to talk about those
stories which I don't generally just
talk about in a YouTube
video I definitely caught hackers I've
definitely hacked people before not
going to talk about it right now um I've
definitely social engineered people
before am I going to teach you that in
the Boost no we're not going to talk
about that stuff in the Boost let's just
say that the techniques and the and the
skills that you learn in the beginner
boost the basic things particularly
shell things like shell scripting how to
write your own uh trip wire so you can
catch any hacker without any special
code which is how I caught the hackers
who invaded my system these are all
things that are going to be just basic
Linux terminal skills and understanding
networking and understanding how to use
your computer how understanding how to
how to read assembly understanding how
memory overflow even works which you
cannot understand unless you learn C
this is why you should learn C before
any other language if you want to do a
lowlevel kind of thing you really should
and you should probably learn assembly
we're not going to do assembly so the
answer is yes and I mean this so I but
and my story is simply that once I got
talking to you know professionals
including owners of cyber security firms
uh on our stream who were retracted in
this was back when I was averaging 3
four 500 people per stream and to tell
you the truth I I've never averaged over
a hundred now and I love it because I
like having a tiny little community of
people that uh can put up with my crap
and uh are more focused um when we had
that many people it was really hard to
to see everything and they were here
because of the hacking they wanted to
learn how to hack and when all of us
found out that hacking is actually a
pretty boring job and this is coming
from the people who owned hacking
companies who were reporting on their
jobs most of hacking most of the hacking
profession the security analyst
profession uh most of it for most people
is writing reports is about 50% writing
reports and doing your thing and you
know it's just running scripts that
already exist like you know Metasploit
and other stuff like that to to do the
pen testing it's basically this a really
you know
glorified um it's basically software
quality assurance with
tattoos that's really what it is it's
like oh I have tattoos but I'm
ultimately I'm doing you know quality
assurance and penetration we'll call it
penetration testing but really I'm just
testing you know Baseline security which
you should be doing anyway if you are
testing your systems you should be
testing your security anyway so security
this isn't a job pentesting is zero day
Discovery is you know red teaming
setting up your defenses that's just
good
operations so it's no surprised that I
ended up taking a very awesome
infrastructure engineering job where I
get to write a bunch of go to do apis
and I can do the security thing I
regularly bring up security concerns I
actually wrote um a protocol API that
that that tunnels through SSH um in
order to submit machine learning jobs
etc etc so I got to do all this really
fun stuff related to hacking that most
people would associate with hacking but
I got to do it just as an operations
engineer as an infrastructure engineer
so so you know when you when you you
know if if a lot of people who get into
hacking they get into it because of the
lifestyle the hacker lifestyle they they
want to look like a hacker they want to
put you know their hoodie on they want
to do that that's why I have a hoodie on
by the way they they just they don't get
what the job is in fact some some of the
best hackers in the world are very plain
looking you would never know it and a
lot of them work for the government some
of the best opportunities to hack are
you can either work for one of these
edgy cyber security firms like um what
is it f security there's actually a
security firm called FSE security I know
isn't that cliche they literally call
themselves FSE
security and their job postings are like
so I'm going to get hacked because I'm
making fun of them they're so edgy it's
like well we might consider if you have
a certification as long as it's ocp but
generally speaking we don't consider
certifications level of your hacker
prowess I'm like okay where's my
copy I got to tell you the truth hacker
lifestyle culture
thing I mean part of me kind of likes it
I'm not going to lie there's a young
part of me that still likes it but
mostly I'm like yeah
okay hold my beer while I get actual
work done including security for
infastructure Engineers that most of the
infrastructure the the point I'm trying
to make is that infrastructure
engineering and uh to some degree even
devops believe it or not is in the
hacker you know skill space and that
hacking and security applies to
everything and I have run into so much
bad code that has no Baseline
consideration for security and you're
like what the hell are they doing here
because they're not thinking like a
hacker and that's another video I'm
going to do another video about thinking
like a hacker this video is specifically
to answer the question will we be
including cyber security in the Boost
the answer is yes but we are not
explicitly going to call it cyber
security the things are Baseline for
that um and you know there's a lot of
great places you can go to learn that
the the first entire just to make my
case the very the first entire module in
I think it was try hackme it was either
try hackme or hack the box is all Linux
learning Linux and it was filled with
errors like really substantial errors
about how to use Linux in the command
line and I in fact I made a video about
it I'm not going to give it to you right
now you're going to have to go find it
there's a video of us going through it
and I was just laughing at everything I
was like this is so totally wrong in
fact one of my Clips is me talking
directly to the person who made the
Linux module for one of these Services
it was absolutely laughable how wrong it
was and and I was like
okay and that just makes the point that
the beginner boost is going to teach you
things you know how to use a command
line how to deal with permissions
properly how to you know how to organize
stuff Bas systems Administration for
Linux these are things that a lot of
security people don't understand they
they know how to hack a thing but they
don't understand some of the broader
Concepts they can never even articulate
the unix's philosophy to you so in my
opinion you're going to be more prepared
to go into a cyber security career after
completing the Boost uh you know and and
doing that deep diving the way you need
to so that's all I have to say about
that I read a couple comments
here uh
okay
uh is my Cur out of curiosity is my work
checked by Security in any way
absolutely um my work uh the code that I
write and the apis that I write and
things like that have to pass a security
audit all the time and so things about
whether or not you you know you bring
containers directly into your
environment things like these are all
security concerns these will be things
so bottom line as we talk about all the
things in the beginner boost security is
always going to be a consideration in
the thing that we're talking about and
it always should be security is a
profession but it is also a mindset and
a priority across all of the all of the
applications I mean all of the um what I
want to say titles and all of the job
categories that that we try to prepare
you for for the beginner boost they're
all in Tech and you know really should
learn to think to have a a security
mindset no matter what it is you end up
doing